五街
先生
Mister?
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎来到圣何塞国际机场
welcome to San Jose International Airport.
地面交通&候车区
救命
Help!
-亚当  -天啊
- Adam?! - Oh, my God!
亚当
Adam?!
快打911
Somebody call 911!
天啊
Oh, my God!
我是医生  让我看看  让我看看
I'm a doctor, let me take a look. Let me take a look.
他的颈静脉被割破了
His jugular vein's been cut.
谁有干净的布
Does anyone have a clean cloth?
拜托了  谁有
Please. Someone!
我包里有干净的换洗衣服
I have a fresh change of clothes in my bag.
可以
That's great.
你这是在害他
You're killing him.
我在救他  他快流血而死了
I'm saving his life. He was bleeding out.
不  你放错地方了
N-- You have it in the wrong place.
我还没忘记解剖学入门章节
I think I remember enough of Anatomy 101
知道颈静脉在哪
to know where the jugular vein is.
他如果是成年人  你就找对地方了
You would be in the right place if he were an adult.
但他还没成年  他还是个孩子
He's not an adult. He is a boy.
就是说你也按住了他的气管
Which means you're also putting pressure on his trachea.
就是说他现在没法呼吸
Which means he's not currently breathing.
你得按压上面一点的位置
You have to put the pressure higher up.
这里
There. ‭
一块玻璃  他会没事的
Some glass. He'll be fine.
你是谁
Who are you?
你好  我是肖恩·莫菲医生
Hello. I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
是圣何塞圣文德医院的外科住院医师
I'm a surgical resident at San Jose St. Bonaventure Hospital.
良     医
第一季  第一集
自闭症是一种精神疾病
Autism -- a mental condition characterized by difficulty
表现为交流障碍  语言障碍和理解障碍
in communicating and using language and abstract concepts.
定义是这么说的
That's the definition.
动手术时能允许这种状况吗
Does it sound like I'm describing a surgeon?
他不是「雨人」
He's not Rain Man.
幽闭症患者的俗称
他是高功能自闭症患者  生活能自理
He's high functioning, he's capable of living on his own,
也能处理好自己的事
capable of managing his own affairs.
「高功能」
"High functioning"?
这是新的招聘标准吗
Is that our new hiring standard?
要是的话  你就不会在这了
If it were, you wouldn't be here.
抱歉  真的有必要吗  真的吗
I'm sorry. Is this really necessary? Really?
有必要召开董事会特别会议吗
A special meeting of the Board of Directors --
虽然我很喜欢见到各位
as much as I love you all --
就为了质疑我的聘用决定
questioning one of my hiring decisions?
你在查阅字典的时候  有没有查一下
Did you bother to look up the definition of "President"
「总裁」是什么意思
while you were skimming the dictionary?
你是要请他来做外科住院医生
You're hiring him to be a surgical resident --
那是我的部门  不顾我的反对
my department -- over my objections.
两位  马库斯  别掺杂个人情绪
Marcus, stop making everything so personal.
我掺杂个人情绪
I made it personal?
你打一开始就想要他这位置
You've wanted his job since day one.
在座各位都知道
Everyone in this room knows that.
亚伦  没错  这是你的医院
And, Aaron, yes, this is your hospital.
但医院的运转资金来自我管理的基金会
But the money it takes to run it comes from the Foundation I control.
都和气一点  好吗
So let's all play nice, shall we?
别站那表现出一副很震惊的样子
Stop acting like you're stunned that you're standing there.
你让我们也很震惊
You tried to slip one past us.
我对他和其他候选人一视同仁
I vetted him like I would any other candidate.
你真的认为董事会
And you genuinely thought that this Board
不会对聘用一个有自闭症的
wouldn't reasonably have any doubts
外科医生提出合理的质疑吗
about hiring a surgeon who's been diagnosed with autism?
解释一下你的决定
So justify your decision.
我在肖恩·莫菲十四岁时遇见的他
I met Shaun Murphy when he was 14 years old.
我当时住在怀俄明州
I was living in Wyoming at the time.
他从那时到现在一直是很特别的小伙子
He was, and he still is, an extraordinary young man.
他确实有自闭症  但他也有学者综合征
Yes, he has autism, but he also has savant syndrome --
在多个方面有超乎常人的能力
genius-level skills in several areas.
他记忆超群  还具有空间智力
He has almost perfect recall. He has spatial intelligence.
他观察和分析事物的角度
And he sees things and analyzes things
异于常人  十分独特
in ways that -- that are just remarkable.
从我们甚至无法理解的角度出发
In ways that we can't even begin to understand.
这是优势啊  对医生来说无可争辩的优势
Those are assets. Undeniable assets for any doctor,
尤其是外科医生
particularly a surgeon.
他十四岁时你就认识他了
You've known him since he was 14?
你关心他  把他视如己出
You care about him. He's like a son to you.
安德鲁斯医生  你的妻子对你会非常失望的
Dr. Andrews, your wife is gonna be very upset with you.
如果你想把这扭曲成是在任人唯亲
If you're trying to turn this into a nepotism case,
那我们只能炒了她那位在医院记账的蠢货外甥
we're gonna have to fire her idiot nephew from bookkeeping.
抱歉  你见到克莱尔了吗
Sorry. You seen Claire?
能把灯关了吗
Would you turn off the light?
好  你见到克莱尔了吗
Sure. You seen Claire?
怎么了  麻烦把灯关了
Why? Would you turn off the light?
梅伦德斯想给104号病患动手术
Melendez wants to operate on 104,
但克莱尔还没拿到知情同意书
but Claire hasn't gotten informed consent.
她都不答复呼叫  见到她了吗
And she's ignoring her page. You seen her?
没有  快出去  把灯关上
No. Now go away and turn off the light.
好
Sure.
他们需要你去...
They need you to, um...
听到了
I heard.
她真烦人
Oh, she's such a bitch.
不
No.
她只是不喜欢你
She just doesn't like you.
有点傻吧
It's kind of silly, isn't it?
或许吧
Maybe.
准确来说
To say for sure,
我得知道你在说什么
I'd need to know what it is you're talking about.
我们
Us.
一点也不傻
Not silly at all.
其实还挺好玩的
Quite a bit of fun, actually.
我是说我们在搞的地下情
I meant that we're hiding it. Our relationship.
杰瑞德  我们没有「情」
Jared, we don't have a relationship.
只有「性」
We have sex.
但如果你想告诉大家
But, if you want to tell people
你和我上床的事  我不介意
that you're screwing me, go for it.
中间贵要静脉
头静脉
穿静脉
肘正中静脉
前臂正中静脉
静脉扩张是胸腔内的胸内压上升造成的
他左臂里的静脉在跳动
The veins in the boy's left arm are popping.
那很糟吗
Is that bad?
我不明白
I-I don't see.
胸内压
Intrathoracic pressure.
不是  他的胸部有起伏  他在呼吸
No, his chest is rising. He's breathing.
不对  他的胸部起伏不正常
No, the -- the chest is moving paradoxically.
他的左肺受伤了
The left lung is in distress.
气胸是一种罕见的致命症状
治疗重点是要找出根本病因  再进行修复
没错
Yes.
谁有锋利的小刀  刀刃十多厘米长的
Who here has a sharp knife, blade five inches or longer?
都没有吗
Nobody?
你应该给他做人工呼吸
You should start artificial respiration.
他很快就没办法呼吸了
He's going to stop breathing very soon.
我感觉很好
I feel fine.
梅伦德斯医生想要今天给你做手术
Dr. Melendez would like to do the surgery today.
你急需做这个心脏搭桥手术
You need bypass surgery quite urgently.
请你签一下知情同意书好吗
Would you please sign the consent?
不要
No.
你害怕了
You're scared.
我  我不怕
I-I'm not scared.
你应该害怕
Well, you should be.
我们会把你的胸部切开
We're gonna cut your chest open,
让你的心跳暂停
we're gonna stop your heart,
修复之后再让它重新跳动
repair it and restart it.
你真的想告诉我  你不害怕吗
Are you seriously telling me that that doesn't scare you?
我只想再听听其他意见
I just want a second opinion.
卡勒姆  昨天的你还拥有完美的人生
Callum, yesterday, your life was perfect.
你打着网球  庆祝着周年纪念日
You were playing tennis, you had a big anniversary.
但现在你躺在医院病床上
Today, you're lying in a hospital bed
想着要怎样和你未成年的孩子告别
trying to figure out the best way to say goodbye,
而且还有可能是永别
maybe forever, to your teenage children.
你为什么要说这些
Why are you doing this?
因为我不喜欢别人撒谎
Because I can't deal with lies.
如果你不跟我说实话  我也帮不了你
If you lie to me, my answers won't help you.
但如果你是害怕了  我可以帮你
But, if you're scared, I can help you.
我害怕了
I'm scared.
知道了
Okay.
-你不能回到这里  -我需要一把刀
- You can't be back here. - Oh, I need a knife.
你们把刀放在哪里
Where do you keep the knives
就是从旅客那里没收的刀
people forget they're traveling with?
刀  没问题  还需要其他东西吗
A knife? Sure. Anything else?
我还需要一根两米长的细管子
I do also need a narrow six-foot tube
高浓度酒精  手套和处理行李的胶带
and high-proof alcohol and gloves and baggage-handling tape,
但我会去免税店买酒
but I am going to get the alcohol from the duty-free store
管子我会去汽水贩卖机后面取
and the tube from the back of a soda machine.
那我祝你好运
Well, I wish you all the luck with that.
但我不会给你刀的
But I'm not gonna give you a knife.
不是  我需要一把刀  这很...
No, I need a knife. It-It's -- It's very --
有紧急医疗事故  有紧急医疗事故
There is a medical emergency. There's a medical emergency.
就那把  就那把
That one. That one,
靠近上面那把  看起来很锋利
right near the top, looks very sharp.
你可以把那把刀给我吗
Would you get it for me?
不行  我不会给你刀的  我要问...
No, I'm not gonna give you a knife. I'll ask --
没时间了
‭There's not the time.
小心武器  小心武器
Weapon! Weapon!
让开  快让开
Move! Get out of the way!
放下刀
Drop it.
你这个蠢货  你该庆幸我们没开枪
You idiot! You're lucky we didn't just shoot.
不要  他在想办法救我儿子
No! He's trying to save my son's life.
拿到104床的知情同意书了吗
You get that consent on 104?
我和他做了个交易
Well, I made him a deal.
他六点去见精神科的马克斯医生
He's got a meeting with Dr. Max from psychiatry at 6:00,
八点之前我们会拿到他的同意书
we'll get the consent by 8:00,
明天一早就可以做手术了
we can operate first thing in the morning.
你的解剖学考试过了的吧  布朗医生
You did pass anatomy, right, Dr. Browne?
他是心脏有问题  不是大脑
His problem's in his heart, not his head.
他没有做好手术的心理准备
He's not psychologically ready for surgery.
很快他就会没问题了
He will be. Soon.
他身体上已经准备好了
Well, he is physically ready.
去让他把同意书签了
So, get the consent.
我们正在准备六号手术室
We're prepping O.R. 6 now.
我需要跟你讲讲有十七项研究表明
Do I need to cite you the 17 studies that show a correlation
病患态度和手术结果之间有紧密联系吗
between attitude and outcome in surgical patients?
我需要提醒你我是你的上级吗
Do I need to remind you that I am your superior?
你知道上级的反义词是什么吧
You do know what the opposite of superior is, right?
下属  难道
Subordinate. Doesn't --
对  是下属  也可以说是下级
Sure. Subordinate. Or...inferior.
都一样
Either way.
那也不代表我是错的
It doesn't mean I'm wrong.
可能吧
I suppose not.
但那代表着你必须得装作你错了
But it does mean you have to act like you're wrong.
他心里很慌
He's panic stricken.
昨天的他还年轻又健康
Yesterday, he was young and healthy.
现在他却可能会死
Today, he's mortal.
给他个机会让他想想这件事吧
Just give him a chance to wrap his head around that.
卡卢医生
Dr. Kalu?
你能够让104床病人签了这份同意书吗
Do you think you can get me a signed informed consent on 104?
当然
Of course.
谢了
Thank you.
你认为他做得对吗
You think he's right?
我认为他是我的上司
I think he's my boss.
如果我得在我的上司
And if I have to choose between my boss and...
和我的炮友之间做出选择
the woman I'm screwing,
我真的没得选择  对吧
not much of a choice, am I right?
借过  麻烦借过一下
Excuse me. Excuse me, please?
张力性气胸的形成
是因为肺撕裂导致空气
进入到肺部周围的胸膜腔
又无法回到肺里
切口应该在往下数两根肋骨的地方
The incision should take place two ribs down.
这个瓶子有什么用
Okay, well, why the bottle?
空气会持续泄漏并累积
The air will continue to leak and accumulate
直到伤口被修复为止
until the damage can be properly repaired.
这根管子可以把空气放出来
The tube allows the air to get out.
瓶子中的水则可以防止空气再度进入
The water in the bottle stops the air from coming back in.
自制的单向阀门
A homemade one-way valve.
他有呼吸了
He's breathing.
你救了他
You saved his life.
他救了他
He saved his life!
格拉斯曼医生
肖恩  你在哪  我  我...
Shaun, where are you? I-I --
请尽快打给我
Call me as soon as you can, please.
-那是个错误  -我同意
- That was a mistake. - ‭I agree,
不是因为那个新医生  而是你的问题
'cause it's not about the new doctor, this is about you.
他们正在引你上钩  你还就上钩了
They're baiting you. And you're letting them.
-也许吧  -也许什么
- Maybe. ‭- Maybe what?
你说的是什么错误
What mistake are you talking about?
你拿安德鲁斯的外甥开涮了
Your shot at Andrews' nephew.
拜托  那很好笑
Oh, come on. It was funny.
是很好笑  但也很无礼
It was very funny. It was also disrespectful.
你没有对他表示尊重
Well, you don't show him respect.
我想那是因为你并不尊重他
I assume it's because you don't respect him.
向别人表示尊重是因为尊重他们
You show someone respect because you respect them,
或是害怕他们
or because you're afraid of them.
我哪个都不是
I don't fit into either category.
我也哪个都不是
Well, neither do I.
你应该是的
You should.
你能在那个房间里
You're only in that room
只是因为你祖父创建了这家医院
because your grandfather founded this hospital.
我就假装这段对话没有跑题
I'm gonna pretend that this conversation didn't take this tangent,
来聊聊相关的事
and instead focus on something relevant --
聊聊你要输掉的那场辩论
the debate you are losing.
告诉你怎么能赢吧
Here's how you win this.
不要掺杂私人感情  不要突出自己
You don't make it personal. You do not make it about you.
那正是他们想要的  如果你让他们得逞了
That is what they want, and if you give it to them,
你就输了
you will lose.
我得去圣何塞圣文德医院
I need to get to San Jose St. Bonaventure Hospital.
那正是我们要去的地方
That's where we're going.
很好
Good.
表现得像个普通人能有多难
How hard can it be to just act like a normal human being?!
-他不知道怎么做  -屁话
- He doesn't know how. - Bull!
我们现在该怎么办
What are we supposed to do now? Huh?
这已经是他被踢出的第三所学校了
This is the third school he's been thrown out of.
我们会找到别的学校的
We'll find another school.
我们找不到了  因为没有什么会有所改变
No, we won't, 'cause nothing's gonna change.
他们搞不定他  我不怪他们
They can't handle him, and I don't blame them,
因为很显然  我们也搞不定他
'cause obviously, we can't handle him, either.
这次到底发生什么了
What the hell happened this time?
发生了什么
What happened?!
你弄疼他了
You're hurting him.
你做了什么
What did you do?!
-肖恩  -不
- Shaun! - ‭No!
你能别玩你那破兔子了吗
Will you stop petting that stupid rabbit?!
变了
It changed.
这孩子的心电图变了
The boy's ECG changed.
没变  每分钟心跳还是86
It's the same -- 86 BPM.
不是的  刚刚会高一些
No. It used to be higher.
不  刚刚就是86  现在还是86
No, it used to be 86. It's still 86.
刚刚到了这里
It used to come up to here.
低振幅意味着低压
Lower amplitude means lower voltage.
这是怎么回事  什么意思
What's going on? What does it mean?
意思是他正努力在时速60公里的车上
It means he's trying to read 20-year-old equipment
读一台有二十年历史的仪器
while traveling in a vehicle going 40 miles an hour.
你是怎么让他签字的
How did you get him to sign?
我只是告诉他要么签字  要么回家
I simply told him it was either consenting or going home,
然后我给了两张表  让他选一个
then I gave him two forms and told him to pick one.
你强调了违背医嘱出院表中的
And you highlighted the Release Against Medical Advice form
「能会导致死亡或永久性残疾」
that mentions the "Possibility of death or permanent disability"?
干得漂亮
Well done.
给我Metz组织剪和镊子
Hand me the Metz and a pick-up.
我要分离降主动脉
I'm isolating the descending aorta.
血管钳
Vascular clamp.
那是什么
What is that?
在左心房下面...
Under the left atrium...
白色的东西
something white.
那是肺的一部分吗
Is that part of the lung?
是脓
It's pus.
他有结核吗
Did he have TB?
没有  他没有任何...
No, he doesn't have any--
不  不是现在  他有病史...
No, not currently. Does he have a history--
他小一点的时候  有暴露在...
When he was younger, he was exposed to --
这是个脓疮  会...
This is an abscess. It's gonna bur--
抽吸  拿点腹部垫  他的血压在下降
Suction and a lap sponge. His BP's crashing.
两升开口的生理盐水
Two liters saline wide open.
设置为一级  拿两单位红细胞
Set up the level one. Two units packed cells now.
左旋去甲肾上腺素  平均动脉压保持在60
Get Levophed on board and keep that MAP at 60.
开始抽吸  我什么都看不到
Get in there with the suction. I can't see a damn thing.
抽吸
Suction.
如果我们等到明天再做手术
I hope it isn't too upsetting to him
没准他就死病房里了
when he hears he would have died in his room
希望他知道这件事后不会太伤心
if we'd waited until tomorrow.
梅伦德斯医生  有个八岁的小男孩
Dr. Melendez, we've got an incoming 8-year-old male,
气胸  已经稳定了
pneumothorax stabilized,
但是不确定有没有内伤
but undetermined internal injuries.
你想让谁负责这个病患
Who do you want to catch?
克莱尔  这里不需要你了
Claire, I don't think we need you.
这个病患会没事的  现在就去
This patient is gonna be fine...now.
八岁的健康男孩
8-year-old healthy boy,
被破碎的玻璃指示牌扎到
status post encounter with a shattered glass sign.
多处撕裂伤
Numerous lacerations.
-超声  -送到创伤三室  做心电图
- Echo -- - Get him set up in Trauma 3 with an EKG,
全套血检和CT
full blood work and a pan-scan.
我们得做个超声  超声心动图检查
We need an echo-- echocardiogram.
这家伙是谁
Who is this guy?
他在机场帮忙做了急救
He helped with first-aid at the airport.
我是医生  他需要做个超声心动图
I'm the doctor. He needs an echocardiogram.
-你们要带他去哪  -去手术室
- Where are you taking him? - To surgery.
所有的心脏体征都在正常范围内
All cardiac vital signs are within normal range.
你有任何证件吗
Do you have any I.D.?
没有  他的心脏  是他的心脏
No. His... his heart. It's his heart.
他的心脏没问题  待在这儿
His heart is fine. Now stay here.
亚当需要做超声心动图
Adam needs an echocardiogram.
不  安分点  不然就赶你出去
No. Behave yourself. Or you'll be removed from the building.
超声  超声
Echo. Echo.
那是什么
What's that?
一个单向阀
A one-way valve.
他还说这孩子出现了气胸
And he reports the boy suffered a pneumothorax.
真厉害
That is cool.
你觉得我们需要给他做个超声心动图吗
Do you think we should do an echocardiogram?
基于现在的症状
Based on the presenting symptoms,
没有迹象显示需要做超声心动图
which give no indication that an echocardiogram is necessary,
我的回答是不用
I'm going to answer no.
有什么隐情吗
Am I missing something?
没有
No, sir.
手术刀
Knife.
我们一般不治疗兔子  尤其是...
We don't normally treat rabbits, especially --
这是最近的医院了  而且情况紧急
This was the closest doctor place, and it was an emergency.
我看出来了
No, I can see that.
但即使我是兽医  这兔子  也已经死了
But even if I was a vet, the rabbit...is dead.
节哀  孩子们
I'm sorry, guys.
下雨时  所有气味都不一样了
Everything smells different when it rains.
我们现在怎么办
What do we do now?
我觉得  你们应该埋葬它
Well, you should bury him, I guess.
也许  给它举办个像样的葬礼
I don't know, give him a -- a nice funeral.
它去天堂了吗
Has he gone to heaven?
当然  当然  它去了
Yeah, sure. Uh, sure -- sure, he has. Um...
不  我不想让它去天堂  我想让它留在这儿
No, I don't want him to go to heaven! I want him to be here!
这不会重演了
This won't happen again.
当然不会  它已经死了
It can't happen again. He's dead.
我知道
I know that.
我是说  我们不会再遇到这样的事了
I mean, nothing like this is ever going to happen to us,
再也不会
ever again.
因为我们不回家了
Because we're not going home.
我们再也不会回家了
We're never going home again.
我们有彼此  这就够了
We have each other, and that's all we need.
一个外科医生需要懂得沟通
A surgeon needs to communicate --
不只是提供信息
not just information,
还要有同情心  同理心
but sympathy, empathy.
莫菲医生能做到吗
Can Dr. Murphy do that?
他甚至无法按照约定出席面试
He can't even reliably show up for a job interview.
你就准备坐在这里告诉我们
Are you gonna sit here and tell us that there were
没有其他具备同样资格的年轻外科医生
no other equally-qualified young surgeons --
没有类似问题的外科医生
surgeons without this one's...issues?
没有
No.
正因此  我们才更应该雇用肖恩
Which is why -- exactly why -- we should hire Shaun.
我们应该雇用他  因为他有资格
We should hire him because he is qualified
而且他与众不同
and because he is different.
多久之前这家医院
How long ago was it that we wouldn't hire
还拒绝雇用黑人医生
black doctors in this hospital?
多久之前这家医院
How m-- How long ago was it that we wouldn't hire
还拒绝雇用女医生
female doctors at this hospital?
这么说你认为美国黑人和女性
So, you're comparing being African-American
与患有自闭症是同等的
or a woman with being autistic.
请继续
Please, go on...
好的
Okay.
合理化也是一样
The rationalization is exactly the same.
类似「性格脾气」以及
Words like "Temperament" and,
「天啊  病患们会作何反应」
"Oh, no! How are the patients going to react?"
评价一个人的根据不就是看他如何对待别人吗
Aren't we judged by how we treat people?
我不是指身为医生  我是说身为人
I don't mean as doctors. I mean as people.
尤其是那些不具备和我们同等优势的人
Especially those who-- who don't have the same advantages that we have.
我们雇用肖恩  向有局限性的人给予希望
We hire Shaun, and we give hope to those people with limitations
这些局限性并非他们所认为的那样
that those limitations are not what they think they are,
告诉他们仍有机会
that they do have a shot!
我们雇用肖恩  并因此让医院更好
We hire Shaun, and we make this hospital better for it.
我们雇用肖恩  并因此成为更好的人
We hire Shaun, and we are better people for it.
我们是「更好的人」
We'd be "better people,"
在医疗事故保险上花费更多
spending a lot more on malpractice insurance.
-这孩子多大了  -八岁
- How old is this kid again? - 8.
海绵钳
Spong stick.
五分钟前  他心率多少
What was his heart rate five minutes ago?
Uh, 86.
你确定吗
You sure?
确定  他就像块石头  几乎没变化
Certain. He's been a rock. It's barely changed.
不  哪里变了  哪里不一样了
No, something's changed. Something's different.
你之前问过要不要做心超
You asked earlier about an echo.
没有任何医疗理由  但你还是问了  为什么
You had no medical reason, but you asked anyway. Why?
有个怪人  做了单向阀的人
There was this weird guy, the one that did the one-way valve,
他坚持认为这孩子需要做超声心动图
he kept insisting that the boy needed an echocardiogram.
他没说原因吗
He didn't say why?
他行为很怪异
H-He was really weird.
他的血压在下降  这没理由
His blood pressure's dropping. That makes no sense.
他流血止住了  一切尽在掌控
He's not bleeding anymore. Everything's under control.
做个心超
Do an echo.
这孩子的伤口还没缝合  还得好一会儿
Sir, the boy is wide open. It's gonna take a while.
正好  给我时间搞明白
Good. That'll give me time to figure out
我们为什么需要做心超
why the hell we're doing an echo.
布朗医生  你跟我来
Dr. Browne, you're with me.
我们去找那个怪人
We're gonna go find your weird guy.
让他保持稳定
Keep him stable.
为什么做心超
Why the echo?
好吧  他...他...好吧
Okay. He, uh -- He -- Okay.
他...他...
Uh, he -- Uh, I, uh -- He --
我知道你认为他需要做超声心动图
Okay. I understand you think he needs an echocardiogram.
我们只是想知道原因
We just don't know why.
我注意到心电图的强度
Well, I-I noticed that there was a slight reduction
有轻微的下降
in the intensity of the electrocardiogram.
电流量  我也注意到了
The electrical flow -- I noticed that, too.
心率没变  但振幅下降了
The heart rate was the same, but the amplitude dropped.
心包积液
Pericardial effusion.
减少了心排血量
Reduced cardiac output.
会使其它器官灌注减少
Would stress other organs.
导致它们无法正常工作
Causing them to shut down.
对
Yes.
等下
Hold on.
我们马上回来
Yeah, we're coming right back up --
谢谢
Thank you.
他们做了心超  是正常的
They did the echo. It's normal.
没有心包积液
No pericardial effusion.
不  该有的  没有别的解释
No. It has to be. There -- There is no other explanation.
超声正常  这意味着我们浪费了时间
The echo is normal, which means we just wasted our time.
不
N-No.
好吧  跟我来
Okay, um, hey, come with me.
拜托
Come on.
给他们看
Show them.
重播
Again.
QRS波群
重播
Again.
这儿
There.
我看着正常
Looks normal to me.
这不正常
It's not normal.
右心房有凹陷性畸形
There's a concave deformity in the right atrium.
没有
No, there's not.
有  有的  很轻微
Yeah. Yes, there is. It's very subtle.
就算你是对的
Even if you are right,
也不应该出现心包积液
that's not where a pericardial effusion manifests.
不常见
Not usually.
但...但可能
But it -- it could.
这小孩被砸了一身的碎玻璃  切到了颈静脉
This kid was sprayed with glass shards -- cut his jugular.
如果有片玻璃进入了血流呢
What if a piece of glass entered his blood stream?
它可能从颈静脉
It could have traveled down the jugular vein,
一直流向头臂静脉
into the brachiocephalic vein
进入上腔静脉
and on to the superior vena cava.
上腔静脉
室上嵴
如果刺破了上腔静脉
If it punctured the SVC,
血液会从心脏后方渗出
blood could be leaking behind the heart,
限制舒张期心室扩张和血液充盈
restricting the heart's ability to expand and fill during diastole,
降低心脏的效率
reducing the heart's efficiency.
太多假设了
Lot of ifs there.
陈医生  14号针头
Dr. Chen, pair of 14-gauge on a syringe.
支持批准格拉斯曼医生
All in favor of ratifying Dr. Glassman's decision
雇佣肖恩·莫菲医生的请举手
in hiring Dr. Shaun Murphy?
反对的请举手
All against.
打扰了
Excuse me.
是紧急的医疗情况吗
Is this a medical emergency?
不  不是紧急的医疗情况
No. No medical emergency --
那你就不应该打断
Then you weren't supposed to interrupt --
我知道  但你们得上网看看
Yes, I know, but you need to go online.
-什么网站  -随便哪个
- What? What site? - Pretty much any of them --
推特  YouTube  任何本地新闻网站
Twitter, YouTube, any local news site.
他救了他
He saved his life!
YouTube视频播放量超过二十万次
The YouTube clip already has over 200,000 views.
显然  他是咱们医院的医生
Apparently, he's one of our doctors.
肖恩·莫菲救了这个孩子
Dr. Shaun Murphy saved this boy?
他现在在二号手术室
The boy is in O.R. 2.
梅伦德斯医生不确定他能否活下来
Dr. Melendez isn't sure if he's going to make it.
你未婚夫的刀法不错
Your fiancé sure can handle a knife.
你为什么警告我要尊重安德鲁斯医生
Why did you warn me about respecting Dr. Andrews?
发生什么了
What's going on?
我不能一直保护你
I'm not gonna always be here to protect you.
你认为你会输
You think you're gonna lose?
到最后
Everybody loses...
谁都会输
eventually.
那是你的人吗
Is that your guy?
校车
我们能买个电视吗
Can we get a TV?
不能
No.
为什么
Why not?
因为我们没钱  兄弟
Because we're poor, dude.
我们住在校车里
We live in a bus.
你觉得妈妈会在找我们吗
Do you think Mom is looking for us?
不会
Nope.
她爱我们  但她知道这样更好
She loves us, but she knows it's better this way.
我给你准备了礼物
I got you a present.
今天不是我生日
It's not my birthday.
我还是给你准备了礼物
I got you a present anyway.
这样
Here.
弯钳
Kelly.
布朗医生
Dr. Browne...
你是对的
You were right.
-我不喜欢腌菜  -我知道
- I don't like pickles. - ‭I know.
-我不想吃腌菜  -我检查过了
- I don't want pickles. - And I checked.
你救了那孩子的命
You saved that boy's life.
真好
Oh, good.
他叫亚当
His name is Adam.
创伤性气胸
Traumatic pneumothorax.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
45分钟后董事会重新开会
Board reconvenes in 45 minutes.
我回来之前你在这等我  行吗
Can you stay here until I get back?
好的
Okay.
好
他有着严重的缺陷
He's got a serious deficit.
因为他的缺陷  今天有个孩子活下来了
A child is alive today because of that deficit.
明天可能有人会因此而死
And tomorrow, one may be dead because of it.
我记得我雇你的时候
I seem to remember that when I hired you,
你也并不是一直会做最成熟的决定
you weren't exactly making the most adult decisions.
但你还没治死谁  对吧
You haven't killed anyone yet. Have you?
谢天谢地  有治好年少轻狂的良药
Well, thankfully, there's a cure for youth and stupidity --
也就是时间和经验
time and experience.
治好年少轻狂的良药
There's a cure for stupidity?
好吧
Okay.
真是意外的收获
That would be a windfall.
肖恩有的只不过是个诊断
All Shaun has is a diagnosis.
我需要你的帮助
I'd like your help.
我就当你不会帮我了
I take it I'm not gonna get it.
好吧
Okay.
等一下
Wait.
这孩子什么来头
What's the story with this kid?
为什么对你如此重要
Why is it so important to you?
怎么了
Why not?
把个人感情带到工作中
Because letting things get personal is a sure formula
那肯定是要坏事的
for screwing things up.
是嘛
I don't know.
但正是有了感情
Letting things get personal is how we...
才让我们做得更好
...how we make it matter.
你是骄傲还是失望
So, are you proud or disappointed?
只能选一项吗
Do I have to pick just one?
你是新来的吧
You're new to town, right?
是的
Yes.
我肯定你有很多问题想问
Well, I'm sure you have a lot of questions.
没有
No.
你肯定对这个地方  这里的人充满好奇
You got to be curious about the place, about the people.
格拉斯曼医生给了我医院地图
Dr. Glassman gave me a map of the hospital,
我在网上找了圣何塞的地图
and I got a map of San Jose online.
好吧
Okay.
太棒了
Great.
我确实有一个问题
I do have one question.
什么
Yeah?
为什么我们第一次遇见时你对我那么凶
Why were you rude to me when we first met,
第二次见到时又对我那么好
then nicer to me the second time we met,
现在你又想和我交朋友
and now you want to be my friend?
哪一次是你装出来的
Which time was it that you were pretending?
肖恩  我们走吧
Shaun. We're ready.
投票结果很清楚了  为什么要重新讨论
The vote was clear. Why are we reopening this?
就因为公关的需要吗
Is it really because of a piece of publicity?
因为他刚刚救了一个人的命
It's because the man just saved somebody's life.
那真是谢天谢地了
And thank God for that,
但这不会改变任何我们讨论过的问题
but it doesn't change a single thing we discussed.
给他六个月
Give him six months.
如果他表现得并不是非常出色
If he proves anything less than excellent --
「不是非常出色」就意味着出了人命
Someone "less than excellent" means someone else dies.
我非常乐意满足你的要求  医生
Well, I-I would love to make you happy, Doctor.
我非常希望能聘请从来没有犯过错的医生
I would love to hire someone who never, ever makes a mistake.
但很不巧  上帝已经有工作了
Unfortunately, God already has a job.
我可以承认他对医学有着
I can accept that he will have insights
远超他人的深刻见解
that none of the rest of us will have.
你能说他不会犯下
Can you accept that he will make mistakes
其他人从不会犯的错误吗
none of the rest of us will make?
付出代价的又不是你
You won't be the one who pays the price.
如果肖恩没有展示出我认为他能达到的水平
If Shaun doesn't live up to everything I know he can do,
他会立刻被辞退
he will be immediately released.
我也会辞去我作为医院院长的职务
And I will resign my position as President of this hospital.
我们还没有听过莫菲医生的意见
We haven't heard from Dr. Murphy yet.
我们应该在决定他的命运之前先听听他怎么说
Perhaps we should hear from him before we decide his fate.
肖恩
Shaun...
莫菲医生
Dr. Murphy...
请你说说你为什么想成为一名外科医生
I'd like you to tell us why you want to become a surgeon.
我为什么要和他们做朋友
Why do I want them to be my friends?
每个人都需要朋友  肖恩
Everybody needs friends, Shaun.
会很热闹啊  一起玩捉迷藏
It's gonna be cool, okay? Play hide and seek maybe?
-好吧  -在仓库里涂鸦
- Okay. - ‭Tag in the warehouse?
别再跟着我啦
Hey, stop following me.
跟你说会很好玩的吧
Told ya it was fun, right?
你知道吗
Hey, you know what?
那天  雨的味道像冰淇淋一样
The day that the rain smelled like ice cream,
我的兔子在我眼前去了天堂
my bunny went to heaven in front of my eyes.
那天  老楼里铜水管的味道
The day that the copper pipes in the old building
像烤焦的食物一样
smelled like burnt food,
我的弟弟
my brother...
在我眼前去了天堂
went to heaven in front of my eyes.
我救不了他们
I couldn't save them.
很难过
It's sad.
他们都没有机会长大成年了
Neither one had the chance to become an adult.
他们本应长大成年的
They should have become adults.
他们应该有自己的孩子
They should have had children of their own
并且很爱他们的孩子
and loved those children.
我希望能帮助其他人
And I want to make that possible
实现这一切
for other people.
我还想挣很多钱买一台电视机
And I want to make a lot of money so that I can have a television.
莫菲医生
Dr. Murphy...
很荣幸第一个欢迎你
I want to be the first to welcome you to
来到圣何塞圣文德医院
San Jose St. Bonaventure Hospital.
我们非常高兴和你共事
We're very proud to have you.
肖恩  梅伦德斯医生的团队即将手术
Shaun, Dr. Melendez's team is going into surgery.
当然  如果你感兴趣的话
I mean, if you're interested.
这里真是一团糟
Got a messy field here.
莫菲
Murphy.
吸引器
Suction.
永远记住  你是最聪明的
Never forget, you're the smart one.
你能做好任何事
You can do anything.
我为你骄傲  肖恩
And I'm proud of you, Shaun.
我猜你肯定见过很多例了
Bet you've seen many of these.
我还记得第一例
I remember my first.
不停地想  「肯定好不了了」
Kept thinking, "It doesn't get any better than this."
不过恐怕对你而言  这句话是真的
And for you, I'm afraid, that's literally true.
你是个优秀的孩子  并且显然你非常聪明
You're a nice kid, and you're obviously very smart,
但你不属于这里
but you don't belong here.
所以  只要你到我的团队里
So, as long as you're part of my team,
你就只能拿吸引器
this is all you're ever going to be doing -- suction.
我在医学院见过很多外科医生
I saw a lot of surgeons in medical school.
你比他们出色多了
You're much better than them.
有很多需要我向你学习的地方
I have a lot to learn from you.
但你很自负
You're very arrogant.
这就是你成为优秀的外科医生的凭借吗
Do you think that helps you be a good surgeon?
有没有把你变成一个坏人
Does it hurt you as a person?
值得吗
Is it worth it?